<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.1.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-07-03T23:40:28-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title>Josh Madewell</title><subtitle>JavaScript Enthusiast and Teacher</subtitle><entry><title>How Do You Know So Much?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/how-do-you-know-so-much/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Do You Know So Much?" /><published>2016-07-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-07-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/how-do-you-know-so-much</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/how-do-you-know-so-much/">&lt;p&gt;The question that finally drove me to start this blog…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How do you know so much about JavaScript?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was asked this question at 9:45pm after a 3 hour class I had a bit of trouble answering the question. It was pretty obvious because I babbled on saying something along the lines of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I research everything I can. I watch JS Conference videos, and…I don’t know”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth was, I didn’t know. I started asking myself do I really even know that much about JavaScript? I was debating with myself whether I actually knew very little and it just seemed like a lot to the student or if I really did know a lot. I took a deep breath, a step back, and thought a little longer about the question and decided:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do know a lot about JavaScript. I may not know the most about JavaScript and depending on who you are, I may not know more than &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; do about JavaScript but I have no doubt at all that I know more about the language than your average JavaScript developer does and the reason is quite simple: I know how to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-learn-have-a-drive&quot;&gt;How To Learn: Have a drive.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know if I’m good at learning because I was raised by two teachers (that probably helps) or just because I have a curious mind but there’s one thing that has stood out to me more and more as I progress through my career and it’s that I’m just faster at picking stuff up than other people (aka. learning).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t always like that. My first job to help me get through college was as a Crew Member at Chipotle. I was &lt;em&gt;terrible&lt;/em&gt; at this job. I remember one of the other employees taking me to the office in the back and literally telling me: “Hey, you suck at your job.” I kind of laughed him off because &lt;em&gt;who cares how good you are at making a burrito&lt;/em&gt; but this is a crucial part of where I get my drive. Being told to my face that I was terrible at doing what I was doing was pretty eye opening. I don’t remember caring that I sucked at my job (and I did, this guy wasn’t a jerk, he was just honest.) All I remember from that moment is realizing that &lt;strong style=&quot;color: red&quot;&gt;someone else cares about how good you are at what you do&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may &lt;em&gt;seem&lt;/em&gt; like an obvious fact but the problem is not everyone keeps this in mind. I’d bet that most people haven’t been as lucky as I was to have someone actually remind them that this is true. Every single day, you’re being judged. If you’re at work, you’re getting judged by your boss/peers. If you’re in class, you’re getting judged by other students/the teacher. If you’re reading a blog, you’re getting judged by yourself. If you’re writing the blog, you’re getting judged by your readers. People have opinions. That’s how people are and the sooner you realize that people’s opinions &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; matter (to an extent, don’t go crazy on me!) the sooner you can learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-should-other-peoples-opinions-affect-how-i-learn&quot;&gt;Why should other people’s opinions affect how I learn?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to emphasize that it’s not the actual opinions of you that you should worry about. It’s merely the fact that people &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; creating opinions about you. Most likely, you’d prefer someone has good opinions towards you rather than bad (especially if they’re your employer) but still, we don’t care about &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; someone thinks of us. We only care &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; they think of is. Once we care about this, we have &lt;em&gt;a reason&lt;/em&gt; to make sure people draw &lt;em&gt;the best&lt;/em&gt; opinion possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thats-when-i-became-the-best-damn-burrito-maker-ever&quot;&gt;That’s when I became the best damn burrito maker ever.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as I accepted that someone else cared about how good I was at my job, I stepped it up. I opened the station the fastest, I was our best lunch hour order taker, I closed the station the fastest, I cleaned the station the fastest, I did everything I could to &lt;em&gt;be the best&lt;/em&gt; so that the only opinion someone could make of me was: &lt;em style=&quot;color: red&quot;&gt;Damn, he can make a good burrito.&lt;/em&gt;. I went on to learn multiple other stations with the goal of being the best at each one until I was offered my first programming gig a year later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-when-do-i-start-learning&quot;&gt;So when do I start learning?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, as soon as you realize and accept what I’ve just explained, you’re going to start learning. There won’t be any tricks. You’re going to have a reason to be better at what you do. You’re going to have &lt;em&gt;the drive&lt;/em&gt; to be the best &lt;em&gt;whatever&lt;/em&gt; that you can be but that doesn’t mean I can’t provide you with a few of my own tricks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-learn-the-rules&quot;&gt;How To Learn: The Rules&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These four rules should help you become a better learner:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Learn how to Google and don’t be afraid to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;This deserves it’s own blog post (and will get it). Googling is not hard but it sure as hell isn’t easy either. Some people think they shouldn’t Google because they feel they should already know the answer or should be able to get it from their own resources (class lectures, books, etc.) but when we have the power of the entire internet at our fingertips, we should be using it. This is an important rule #1.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When you answer your question. Ask another question about the answer.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;This can be hard to do and it can be harder to keep up with but what motivates me is remembering two things: First, you already know it: someone cares about how good I am at what I do and second, that same someone cares about how good my peers are at how they do what they do.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;If I take the time to get learn &lt;em&gt;one more thing&lt;/em&gt; about any given concept than one of my peers then I’m going to always be one step ahead of that peer. If I’m always a step (or more) ahead of my peers then that someone who cares has damn good reason to think higher of me than any of my peers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Don’t ever leave a question unanswered.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Sometimes you don’t have a choice but if you do ever have the option to &lt;em&gt;just move on&lt;/em&gt;, do yourself a huge favor and &lt;strong style=&quot;color: red&quot;&gt;don’t&lt;/strong&gt;. I’ve spent entire days just learning about a concept that I didn’t understand. When I was done, not only did I understand, I felt like I could teach a class or write a dissertation on the subject. I’m not saying ignore your job and worry about yourself (&lt;strong&gt;although that can definitely be a healthy thing to do every now and again&lt;/strong&gt;) but I am saying don’t waste your time starting to research a question only to do yourself the &lt;strong&gt;great disservice&lt;/strong&gt; of never finding an answer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Teach what you’ve learned to some(one/thing) else.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;This is a situational step. If you’re learning how to add 4 to 5, then you might need to be a first grade teacher to find someone to teach but more often than not, there’s someone you can share your findings with. Maybe start a blog? Maybe host a lunch and learn and invite anyone at your company who will listen? Teach your spouse. Teach your dog. Teach your rubber duck! Speaking out loud about something is great and speaking out loud to someone who is capable/willing to ask questions back to you is invaluable.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully you got something out of reading this post. I plan on delving further into these four steps in future blog posts but as always if you have any questions at all feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:josh.madewell@gmail.com&quot;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; me and I’d love to talk about anything I’ve discussed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Josh out.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="rules" /><category term="learning" /><summary>The question that started the blog.</summary></entry><entry><title>Who Am I?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/who-am-i/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Who Am I?" /><published>2016-06-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-06-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/who-am-i</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/who-am-i/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;short-biography&quot;&gt;Short Biography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Josh Madewell. I was raised in Kissimmee, FL by my loving parents who both happen to be teachers. I graduated from Florida State University in 2013 with a Bachelor of Science in Computer Science. Six months before graduating, I got my first job as an Associate Software Developer at PATLive (now known as Tresta). After working at PATLive for just over a year and a half, I decided that Tallahassee was not the place for me and moved to Austin, TX. I’ve held two full-stack web developer jobs in Austin both focusing on the MEAN stack. I’m currently employed at Q1Media as a Web Developer. I am also currently a TA with The Coding Bootcamp at UT Austin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;personal-interview&quot;&gt;Personal Interview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Where do you see yourself in 5 years?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been asked this a few times in my life. My answers used to be back when I wasn’t even out of high school and I said that I was going to be a doctor. Times sure have changed. Now, if I hear this question, it’s usually in an interview or a 1:1 with my current employer and when I answer this question with “coding” I’m usually asked what that means. So in case you’re asking the same thing: It means I love what I’m doing. I love to code. When I get home from work one of my favorite things to do right now is to pull out my laptop and start hacking away at something. It doesn’t matter to me if that something is work related, a personal project, an open source project, or freelance, when I’m coding, I’m happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What is it you enjoy &lt;em&gt;most&lt;/em&gt; about coding?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thrill of completing something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is literally no greater feeling than hacking away at a problem for three hours straight, refreshing the browser, and then finally seeing the result you expected when you started. Every time this happens there’s a mini victory dance that goes on in my head reminding me why I love to code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Why the blog?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to be addressing this a little bit more in my next post but the main reason for this blog is going to be to help people learn how to self learn (sorry, that’s a mouthful). I’ve always wanted to blog, I’ve always had plenty of thoughts and things to blog about but never really had a good drive getting me to do it until yesterday when a student asked me the seemingly simple question: “How do you know so much about JavaScript?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This question, I thought was super easy to answer but then it occurred to me that it’s actually a really hard question. Sure, I can say “I read about everything” or “I’ve done my research” but that doesn’t mean anything to someone who’s actually interested. They want to learn &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; I know so much. So I’m going to try and teach that with this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Is this a coding only blog?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t want my blog to be about coding only. It may be my favorite hobby and something I enjoy talking about but there’s two things I enjoy almost as much. Budgeting and playing Poker. They are quite unrelated to coding but they are two things that I could talk all about for hours so they will definitely be blogged about at some point. If anyone has specific request then please &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:joshmadewell@gmail.com&quot;&gt;contact me!&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How often will you post?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to post at least once a week but it could be more and it could be less. At the beginning it’ll probably be a bit more and then it’ll slow down as I keep going but I definitely want to keep going and just keep putting my thoughts out there.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary>A quick description of who Josh Madewell is</summary></entry></feed>
